

# Samy CHBINOU

DevOps Engineer

ANTIBES, FR

samy.chbinou@esna.cloud

https://chbinousamy.github.io/resume/resume.pdf

# **BACKGROUND**

# **ABOUT**

51 years old, Telecom & Software engineering education, I worked in software industry on real time embedded applications for mobile phones, IP multimedia set top boxes. Lately I did Proof of Concepts for Cloud Native infrastructure platforms for Machine Learning, called MLOps, That is DevOps for Machine Learning applications.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## DevOps, NAVYA

Sep, 2021 - Oct, 2021 1 month

NAVYA Drive delivers autonomous driving. In a Agile team of 5 persons I added Gitlab pipelines automation for Continuous Integration Tests. I also setup some Gitlab runners to handle load CI tests. Directly installed on Bare Metal and on some VMs, Virtualbox and AWS

- CI pipelines on Gitlab runners
- Docker Buildx Python Containers
- o MaaS SRE
- Terraform on local VMs and AWS

#### Artificial Intelligence Engineer, VALEO

May, 2021 - Jul, 2021 2 months

Valeo. In the transversal GEEDS entity, I assist in relocation of the R&D Datacenter from Paris to Créteil.

- Buildx Nvidia Docker Containers
- Assistance in relocating a Datacenter from Paris to Creteil

### Platform Engineer, Nokia Bell Labs

Oct, 2014 - Dec, 2020 6 years 2 months

Nokia Bell Labs. I worked as freelance in a 'StartUp Garage'. I setup a small hardware platform to make some tests on different types of technologies: storage databases, ethernet over fiber, docker containers and kubernetes clusters, Machine Learning DevOps pipelines

- o Docker, Kubernetes, Databases Storage, Private Cloud and ServerLess platforms
- Machine learning and Neural Networks Data engineering
- Benchmarking CPU Offloading on Nvidia GPU, FPGA
- Benchmarking Ethernet over Optical Fiber (RDMA)

## Software Test Engineer, Ercom, Thales Subsidiary

Apr, 2006 - Apr, 2013 7 years 1 month

Ercom is a Thales Subsidiary. I worked in a 10 people Télécom team on Mobipass product, a Functionnal and Stress Test for eNodeB and 4G/LTE Mobiles. As Software engineer, I developped a User Interface in .NET C# language and did many tests on Network Data Encoding and Decoding.

- Integration and Validation Tests
- Network Data Blocks Encoding and Decoding
- C#.NET UI software development
- Functionnal and Stress Tests of eNodeB and 4G/LTE Mobiles

# **SKILLS**



Digital Communication Systems & Technology, MSc. Engineer, CHALMERS - Göteborg, SWEDEN

Sep, 1996 - Sep, 1997

Telecom and Software Engineering, Engineer, IMT Atlantique (ex Télécom Bretagne)

Sep, 1994 - Jun, 1996

#### **INTERESTS**

#### **Traveling**

Gardening

Open Source